Bakhtiyar Zubairov

Minsk, Belarus

irookanji@gmail.com, +375-44-418-07-86

Desire to be a part of vibrant and leading organization and create footprints as a Quality assurance Engineer, to assist the organizations in all aspects by utilizing all my skills, knowledge, abilities and experience with a balance of hands-on, management and leadership responsibilities. Open for relocation.

Experience

SEP 2019 - PRESENT (Minsk, Belarus)

Senior Software Testing Engineer at Petrofac (employed by EPAM Systems)

- Took a leading role in testing, actively involved in creation of detailed test plans test cases and test scenarios for different application modules according to functional requirements and business specifications as well as improve UI\UX Design of company software products
- Helped to establish the QA process, the percentage of coverage with auto-tests increased to 80%, which allowed to get a quick feedback about defects and reduced the appearance of critical errors on the production environment by three times
- Participated in the expansion of the QA-team, conducted interviews, was a mentor, trained, helped to immerse newcomers into the project
- Suggested using the Shift-Left testing approach, this allowed to prevent errors at the early stages of the development phase (misunderstanding, unclear requirements) by 75%
- Functional Testing, Telerik Fiddler, MongoDB, A/B Testing, UML

FEB 2018 - SEP 2019 (Minsk, Belarus)

Software Testing Engineer at EPAM Systems

- Performed smoke, functional, regression, stress, bug verification testing
- Created and executed automation UI tests with Python + Selenium
- Designed, created, and executed functional test cases for product releases to ensure quality products that satisfy industry requirements and stakeholders' needs
- Verified and validated releases, fixes and enhancements by executing test cases to ensure product stability
- Functional Testing, Python, MySQL, Decision Trees

FEB 2016 - JAN 2017 (Karaganda, Kazakhstan)

Junior Software Testing Engineer (employed by EPAM Systems)

- · Analyzed requirements and developed test plans, test scenarios, and test cases
- Executed test cases for functional, validation, end-to-end, and regression testing for Web application
- · Created detailed functional and system/integration test plans
- Performed SQL statements for set up data and retrieved data for tests
- Analyzed applications and errors, escalated issues to developers, and verified fixes

Education

2000 - 2004

University named after D.A. Kunaev (BCs Computer Science)